focaljet.com 2015-12-06

# The Complete Ford Focus Enthusiast Site

Focaljet Privacy Policy   
  
Your privacy is important to us. So we’ve developed a Privacy Policy that covers how we collect, use, disclose, transfer, and store your information. Please take a moment to familiarize yourself with our privacy practices and let us know if you have any questions.Collection and Use of Personal Information  
  
Personal information is data that can be used to uniquely identify or contact a single person.

You may be asked to provide your personal information anytime you are in contact with Focaljet. Focaljet and its affiliates may share this personal information with each other and use it consistent with this Privacy Policy. They may also combine it with other information to provide and improve our products, services, content, and advertising.

Here are some examples of the types of personal information Focaljet may collect and how we may use it.

What personal information we collect  

  * When you create a Focaljet screen name, post in the forums, send private messages, purchase a product from our online store, or participate in an online survey, we may collect a variety of information, including your IP address, name, mailing address, phone number, email address, or contact preferences.

How we use your personal information  

  * From time to time, we may use your personal information to send important notices, such as communications about changes to our terms, conditions, and policies. Because this information is important to your interaction with Focaljet, you may not opt out of receiving these communications.
  * We may also use personal information for internal purposes such as auditing, data analysis, and research to improve Focaljet’s products, services, and user communications.
  * If you enter into a sweepstakes, contest, or similar promotion we may use the information you provide to administer those programs.

  * We may occasionally send you special offers or information on behalf of our sponsors. Each of these will always include an opt-out link.

Collection and Use of Non-Personal Information  
  
We also collect non-personal information − data in a form that does not permit direct association with any specific individual. We may collect, use, transfer, and disclose non-personal information for any purpose. The following are some examples of non-personal information that we collect and how we may use it:

  * We may collect information such as occupation, language, zip code, area code, unique device identifiers, location, and the time zone where a Focaljet user is located so that we can better understand customer behavior and improve our services, and user experience.
  * We also may collect information regarding user activities on our website. This information is aggregated and used to help us provide more useful information to our users and to understand which parts of our website, products, and services are of most interest. Aggregated data is considered non-personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.
  * If we do combine non-personal information with personal information the combined information will be treated as personal information for as long as it remains combined.

Cookies and Other Technologies  
  
Focaljet’s website, private message system, email messages, advertisements, and the Tapatalk.com mobile app may use “cookies” and other technologies such as pixel tags and web beacons. These technologies help us better understand user behavior, tell us which parts of our website people have visited, and facilitate and measure the effectiveness of advertisements and web searches. We treat information collected by cookies and other technologies as non-personal information. However, to the extent that Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or similar identifiers are considered personal information by local law, we also treat these identifiers as personal information. Similarly, to the extent that non-personal information is combined with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.

Focaljet and our partners also use cookies and other technologies to remember personal information when you use our website, online services, and applications. Our goal in these cases is to make your experience with Focaljet more convenient and personal. For example, logging in allows you to have access every time you return to the site without needing to re-enter your screen name and password.

You may always disable cookies from the Focaljet web site. To do that, please refer to the instructions associated with your particular internet browser. Please note that certain features of the Focaljet website will not be available once cookies are disabled.

As is true of most websites, we gather some information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type and language, Internet service provider (ISP), referring and exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information to understand and analyze trends, to administer the site, to learn about user behavior on the site, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Focaljet may use this information in our marketing and advertising services.

In some of our email messages, we may use a “click-through URL” linked to content on the Focaljet website. When customers click one of these URLs, they pass through a separate web server before arriving at the destination page on our website. We track this click-through data to help us determine interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our user communications. If you prefer not to be tracked in this way, you should not click text or graphic links in the email messages.

Pixel tags enable us to send email messages in a format customers can read, and they tell us whether mail has been opened. We may use this information to reduce or eliminate messages sent to customers. 

Disclosure to Third Parties  
  
It may be necessary − by law, legal process, litigation, and/or requests from public and governmental authorities within or outside your country of residence − for Focaljet to disclose your personal information. We may also disclose information about you if we determine that for purposes of national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance, disclosure is necessary or appropriate.

We may also disclose information about you if we determine that disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce our terms and conditions or protect our operations or users. Additionally, in the event of a reorganization, merger, or sale we may transfer any and all personal information we collect to the relevant third party.

Protection of Personal Information  
  
Focaljet takes precautions — including administrative, technical, and physical measures — to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.

When you post in any Focaljet forum, chat room, or social networking service, the personal information you share is visible to other users and can be read, collected, or used by them. You are responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these instances. For example, if you list your name and email address in a forum posting, that information is public. Please take care when using these features.

Integrity and Retention of Personal Information  
  
Focaljet makes it easy for you to keep your personal information accurate, complete, and up to date. We will retain your personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.Access to Personal Information  
  
You can help ensure that your contact information and preferences are accurate, complete, and up to date by logging in to your accounts User CP (Control Panel) located in the forum menu bar at the top of the forum pages. For other personal information, we make good faith efforts to provide you with access so you can request that we correct the data if it is inaccurate or delete the data if Focaljet is not required to retain it by law or for legitimate business purposes. We may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, are extremely impractical, or for which access is not otherwise required by local law. Access, correction, or deletion requests can be made to Contact Us link located in the footer of every forum page.Children  
  
We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If we learn that we have collected the personal information of a child under 13 we will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible.Third-Party Sites and Services  
  
The Focaljet website and forum may contain links to third-party websites, products, and services. We encourage you to learn about the privacy practices of those third parties.Liability Disclaimer  
  
This website is under no liability to any person or entity in respect of any loss or damage (including consequential loss or damage) which may be suffered or incurred, or which may arise directly or indirectly, in respect of information contained on this site.Privacy Questions  
  
If you have questions or concerns about Focaljet’s Privacy Policy or data processing, please contact us at privacy@focaljet.com. Focaljet may update its Privacy Policy from time to time. When we change the policy in a material way, a notice will be posted on our website along with the updated Privacy Policy.

Last updated: February 22, 2012
